Guide to the Liberty Hyde Bailey papers, 1845-2004
Bailey, Liberty Hyde papers, 1845-2004
- Series VII. Writings
  - Mostly published writings authored, about, or compiled by Bailey, 1874-1950 (Box 17,19)
    - An Ocean Voyage College Speculum Volume 8, No. 4: page 61 Author: L. H. Bailey, November 1888 (Box 19, Folder 14)
      unsigned, but by Bailey
    - Studies of the Types of Various Species of the Genus Carex Memoirs of the Torrey Botanical Club Volume 1, No. 1 Author: L. H. Bailey, May 25, 1889 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - The Contents of Seed Packages Agricultural Science Volume 3, No. 9: pages 227-234 Author: L. H. Bailey, September 1889 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Rules for Naming Vegetables. Report of Committee of Experiment Station Horticulturists. United States Department of Agriculture. Office of Experiment Stations. Circular 11 Author: L. H. Bailey, September 1889 (Box 19, Folder 17)
      Bailey was the Chairman of the Committee
    - The Classification of Slight Varieties Bulletin of the Torrey Botanical Club Bulletin 16: pages 328-329 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1889 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - The Editor's Outlook American Garden Volume 11: pages 616-618 Author: L. H. Bailey, October 1890 (Box 19, Folder 19)
      Subheadings: Fungi and the People, Abandoned Farms, Horticulture at the World's Fair, Ideals for Florists, Botanical Language
    - Horticultural Education Garden and Forest Volume 3: page 259 Author: L. H. Bailey, May 1890 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - The Editor's Outlook American Garden Volume 11, No. 8: pages 483-484 Author: L. H. Bailey, August 1890 (Box 19, Folder 21)
      Subheadings: Cactuses In Place and Out of Place, Botany and Horticulture, A New Charm for Country Life, Protection to Planstmen
    - A New Science American Garden Volume 11: pages 253-256 Author: L. H. Bailey, April 1890 (Box 19, Folder 22)
      A preprint
    - The American Mulbery American Garden Volume 11, No. 8: pages 577-587 Author: L. H. Bailey, October 1890 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Some Attractive Native Plants American Garden Volume 11, No. 10: pages 597-599 Author: L. H. Bailey, October 1890 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - The Agricultural Status Department of Public Instruction, Michigan Agricultural College Author: L. H. Bailey (Box 19, Folder 25)
      Commencement address delivered at M.A.C.
    - Notes from a Garden Herbarium-III [More About the Dewberries] American Garden Volume 12, No.1: pages 82-84 Author: L. H. Bailey, January 1891 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Notes from a Garden Herbarium - IV [The Cultivated Chestnuts] American Garden Volume 12, No.5: pages 276-278 Author: L. H. Bailey, May 1891 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Notes from a Garden Herbarium-VI [The Soulard Crab and Its Kin] American Garden Volume 12, No.8: pages 469-474 Author: L. H. Bailey, August 1891 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - The Japanese Walnut (Juglans Sieboldiana, Maxim) American Garden Volume 11, No. 12: page 708 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1890 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - The Editor's Outlook American Garden Volume 11, No. 12: pages 746-747 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1890 (Box 19, Folder 28)
      Subheadings: The Mission of Flowers, The Discipline of Difficulties, Fungi and the State, The Old Fashioned Gardens
    - Books and Bulletins American Garden Volume 11, No. 12: pages 762-764 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1890 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Brains in Books - A Meaty Review of the Latest Work of the Brain Workers in Horticulture American Garden Volume 12, No. 10: pages 631-632 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1891 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Printed Course and Lecture Outlines Author: L. H. Bailey, 1890-1891 (Box 19, Folder 30)
      e.g. Syllabus of Lecture Upon Vegetables, Why Are Orchards Barren?, The Management of Orchard Lands, The Philosophy and Practice of Pruning, etc.
    - On the Longevity of Apple Trees Privately printed 6 pages Author: L. H. Bailey, 1891 (Box 19, Folder 31)
      3 copies - 2 free copies, the other as pages 1-6 in the book; read before the 24rth annual meeting of the Kansas State Horticultural Society in December 1890
    - Experiences in Spraying Cornell University, College of Agriculture: Bulletin of the Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 18: pages 28-41 Author: L. H. Bailey, July 1890 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Report Upon the Condition of Fruit-Growing in Western New York Cornell University, College of Agriculture: Bulletin of the Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 19: pages 44-58 Author: L. H. Bailey, August 1890 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Tomatoes Cornell University, College of Agriculture: Bulletin of the Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 19: pages 74-87 Author: L. H. Bailey, October 1890 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Sundry Investigations Made During the Year Cornell University, College of Agriculture: Bulletin of the Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 25: pages 171-187 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1890 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Experiences with Egg Plants Cornell University, College of Agriculture: Bulletin of the Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 26:p ages 4-26 Author: L. H. Bailey, March 1891 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Peaches and Yellows in the Chesapeake Country American Garden Volume 12, No. 1: pages 20-23 Author: L. H. Bailey, January 1891 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - The Editor's Outlook American Garden Volume 12, No. 1: pages 41-45 Author: L. H. Bailey, January 1891 (Box 19, Folder 33)
      Subheadings: 1890, The Winter Void, Testing of Varieties
    - The Norfolk Truckers In Mid-Winter American Garden Volume 12, No. 2: pages 103-107 Author: L. H. Bailey, February 1891 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - The Editor's Outlook American Garden Volume 12, No. 2: pages 111-116 Author: L. H. Bailey, February 1891 (Box 19, Folder 35)
      Subheadings: Our Horticultural Status, What is Horticulture?, Control of Plant Diseases, The Geography of Success, Little Known Plants
    - The Editor's Outlook American Garden Volume 12, No. 3: pages 170-171 Author: L. H. Bailey, March 1891 (Box 19, Folder 36)
      Subheadings: The Symbolism of Flowers, Reform in Nomenclature, Play Grounds for Children, The Fruit Exchange
    - Books and Bulletins American Garden Volume 12: pages 126-128 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1891 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Books and Bulletins American Garden Volume 12, No. 1: pages 57-64 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1891 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Books and Bulletins American Garden Volume 12, No. 3: pages 187-192 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1891 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Piece-Roots vs. Whole-Roots American Garden Volume 12, No. 4: pages 218-219 Author: L. H. Bailey, April 1891 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - The Editor's Outlook American Garden Volume 12, No.4: pages 234-236 Author: L. H. Bailey, April 1891 (Box 19, Folder 39)
      Subheadings: The Apple, Suspicious Bulletins, Seed Warranty, In Spring
    - Books and Bulletins American Garden Volume 12, No. 4: pages 252-256 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1891 (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - The Editor's Outlook American Garden Volume 12, No. 5: pages 299-302 Author: L. H. Bailey, May 1891 (Box 19, Folder 41)
      Subheadings: Plant Superstition, Out Grape Interests, Horticulture at the Columbian Exposition
    - Lawson Valentine American Garden Volume 12, No. 6: pages 359-360 Author: L. H. Bailey, June 1891 (Box 19, Folder 42)
    - Books and Bulletins American Garden Volume 12, No. 5: pages 316-320 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1891 (Box 19, Folder 43)
    - The Editor's Outlook American Garden Volume 12, No. 6: pages 361-362 Author: L. H. Bailey, June 1891 (Box 19, Folder 44)
      Subheadings: World's Fair, Truck Farming, Floriculture
    - The Editor's Outlook American Garden Volume 12, No. 7: pages 426-432 Author: L. H. Bailey, July 1891 (Box 19, Folder 45)
      Subheadings: Agricultural Education, Horticultural Congress, Old Prejudices, Fruit Reports
    - The Editor's Outlook American Garden Volume 12, No. 8: pages 495-499 Author: L. H. Bailey, August 1891 (Box 19, Folder 46)
      Subheadings: Florists Display Grounds, Southern Possibilities, Society American Florists, Hard Work, Pleasure En Route
    - Jefferson as a Horticulturist American Garden Volume 12, No. 8: pages 463-464 Author: L. H. Bailey, August 1891 (Box 19, Folder 47)
    - The Farms Must Become Gardens American Garden Volume 12, No. 8: page 456 Author: L. H. Bailey, August 1891 (Box 19, Folder 48)
    - The Greatest Prosperity: Greater Than Millions of Money; Greater Than Glory of Conquest; Greater Than Political Power American Garden Volume 12, No. 8: page 451 Author: L. H. Bailey, August 1891 (Box 19, Folder 49)
    - The Home Lot From Garden o Table American Garden Volume 12, No. 9: pages 559-561 Author: L. H. Bailey, September 1891 (Box 19, Folder 50)
    - The Editor's Outlook American Garden Volume 12, No. 9: pages 562-557 Author: L. H. Bailey, September 1891 (Box 19, Folder 50)
      Subheadings: Better Descriptions, Easy Reading, Fences, Roads and Progress, Wild Garden Lessons, Unreasonable Profits for Nuts, A New Substitution, Teach the Boys, Wild Garden
    - The Home Garden of the Farm; of the Village Lot; of the Town; of the Country Place American Garden Volume 12, No. 9: page 515 Author: L. H. Bailey, September 1891 (Box 19, Folder 51)
    - The Maligned Blackberry American Garden Volume 12, No. 9: page 558 Author: L. H. Bailey, September 1891 (Box 19, Folder 52)
    - Subrosa American Garden Volume 11: pages 615 Author: L. H. Bailey (suspected), 1890 (Box 19, Folder 53)
    - Notes from St. Fereol Se Ponsonby American Garden Volume 12,No. 9: pages 535-537 Author: L. H. Bailey (suspected), September 1891 (Box 19, Folder 53)
    - The Wolf and the Garden. How the Others "Half Live". American Garden Volume 12, No. 10: page 579 Author: L. H. Bailey, October 1891 (Box 19, Folder 54)
    - Full page photo of Hybrid Grape, "Professor Bailey". (V. Lincecumii x Triumph) American Garden Volume 12, No. 10: page 583, 1891 (Box 19, Folder 54)
    - Pines, Hemlocks and Spruces. A Suggestion for Winter Study. American Garden Volume 12, No. 11: pages 646-648 Author: L. H. Bailey, November 1891 (Box 19, Folder 55)
    - Various Lilacs for the Lawn American Garden Volume 12, No. 11: pages 663-665 Author: L. H. Bailey, November 1891 (Box 19, Folder 56)
    - Electro-Horticulture American Garden Volume 12, No. 11: pages 667-671 Author: L. H. Bailey, November 1891 (Box 19, Folder 57)
    - Lecture by Prof. L.H. Bailey of Cornell University, Ithaca, N.Y. The Philosophy of the Crossing of Plants Considered in Reference to Their Improvement Under Cultivation 31 pages Author: L. H. Bailey, 1892 (Box 19, Folder 58)
      Delivered at the Public Winter Meeting of Massachusetts State Board of Agriculture
    - The Home Lot From Garden o Table American Garden Volume 12, No. 10: pages 621-623 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1891 (Box 19, Folder 59)
    - The Editor's Outlook American Garden Volume 12, No. 10: pages 624-625 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1891 (Box 19, Folder 59)
      Subheadings: The Florists' Society, The American Garden and Popular Gardening, World's Fair, The Bountiful Harvests
    - The Forcing of English Cucumbers American Garden Volume 12, No.12: pages 744-747 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1891 (Box 19, Folder 60)
    - Injurious Insects and Plant Diseases, With Remedies Peter Henderson & Co., NY Author: L. H. Bailey, 1892 (Box 19, Folder 61)
    - A New Edible Blackberry - Rubus Millspaughi Agricultural Science Volume 6, No.2: pages 96-97 Author: L. H. Bailey, February 1892 (Box 19, Folder 62)
    - On the Supposed Correlations of Quality in Fruits Agricultural Science Volume 6, No.11: pages 489-502 Author: L. H. Bailey, November 1892 (Box 19, Folder 63)
    - Cross-Breeding and Hybridizing With a Brief Bibliography of the Subject The Rural Library Volume 1, No. 6 Author: L. H. Bailey, April 1892 (Box 19, Folder 64)
    - Agricultural Education And Its Place in the University Curriculum Privately printed; Ithaca, N.Y., Andrus & Church, 1893 20 pages Author: L. H. Bailey, February 1893 (Box 19, Folder 65)
      Lecture Given Before the Agricultural Association of Cornell University, January 31, 1893; 3 copies
    - 24 pages Author: L. H. Bailey, March 1904 (Box 19, Folder 65)
    - Recent Progress in American Horticulture Science Volume 21, No. 519: pages 20-23 Author: L. H. Bailey, January 13, 1893 (Box 19, Folder 66)
    - [Untitled Address Before the "New York Farmers"], January 17, 1893 (Box 19, Folder 67)
    - The Benton Harbor Melon Industry Garden and Forest pages 412-413 Author: L. H. Bailey, October 1893 (Box 19, Folder 68)
    - Is the Experiment Station Movement a Success? The Work in Horticulture Agricultural Science Volume 7, No.10: pages 448-450 Author: L. H. Bailey, October 1893 (Box 19, Folder 69)
    - Electricity and Plant Growing Author: L. H. Bailey, 1894 (Box 19, Folder 70)
      Lecture given at Massachusetts Horticultural Society, February 3, 1894
    - Whence Came the Cultivated Strawberry? The American Naturalist Volume 28: pages 293-306 Author: L. H. Bailey, April 1894 (Box 19, Folder 71)
    - Neo-Lamarkcism and Neo-Darwinism The American Naturalist pages 661-678 Author: L. H. Bailey, August 1894 (Box 19, Folder 72)
    - The Plant Individual in the Light of Evolution Science N.S. Volume 1, No.11: pages 281-292 Author: L. H. Bailey, March 1895 (Box 19, Folder 73)
    - Experimental Evolution Amongst Plants The American Naturalist Volume 27: pages 318-325 Author: L. H. Bailey, April 1895 (Box 19, Folder 74)
      Abstract of an Address before the Massachusetts Horticultural Society, February 23, 1895; 2 copies
    - What Is "High Work"? Science N.S. Volume 2, No. 32: page 164 Author: L. H. Bailey, August 1895 (Box 19, Folder 75)
    - [Review] The Elements of Botany by Francis Darwin Science N.S. Volume 2, No. 49: pages 774-775 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1895 (Box 19, Folder 76)
    - Horticulture at Cornell Science N.S. Volume 2, No 51: pages 831-839 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1895 (Box 19, Folder 77)
    - The Evolution of Tillage Proceedings of the 40th Annual Meeting, The Western New York Horticultural Society pages 85-94 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1895 (Box 19, Folder 78)
      Held at Rochester, January 23-24.1895
    - Variation After Birth The American Naturalist Volume 30: pages 17-24 Author: L. H. Bailey, January 1896 (Box 19, Folder 79)
    - Suggestions for the Planting of Shrubbery Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station - Horticultural Division Bulletin 121 Author: L. H. Bailey, September 1896 (Box 19, Folder 80)
    - The Philosophy of Species-Making Botanical Gazette Volume 22: pages 454-462 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1896 (Box 19, Folder 81)
      An Address Before the Botanical Society of America, August 1896; 2 copies
    - Second Report Upon Extension Work in Horticulture Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station - Horticultural Division Bulletin 122 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1896 (Box 19, Folder 82)
    - The Improvement of our Native Fruits Year of the Department of Agriculture pages 297-304 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1896 (Box 19, Folder 83)
    - The Hamburg Exposition Garden and Forest Volume 10: pages 391-392 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1897 (Box 19, Folder 84)
    - Will The American Farmer Become a Peasant? 31st Annual Report of the Secretary of Connecticut Board of Agriculture for 1897 pages 35-46, discussion: pages 46-56 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1898 (Box 19, Folder 85)
      2 copies; one copy is missing page 56
    - What is Nature-Study? Cornell University, Teacher's Leaflets No. 6: pages 49-52 Author: L. H. Bailey, April 10, 1898 (Box 19, Folder 86)
    - Nature Study: Its Field, Its Methods, and Its Results The Science Teacher and the Journal of Nature Study Volume 1, No. 9: pages 140-145 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1898 (Box 19, Folder 87)
    - Annual Flowers Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station - Horticultural Division Bulletin 161 Author: G. N. Lauman & L. H. Bailey, January 1899 (Box 19, Folder 88)
    - Some Constants of American and European Agriculture Proceedings of the 44th Annual Meeting, The Western New York Horticultural Society pages 15-27 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1899 (Box 19, Folder 89)
    - Farmers' Reading Courses US Department of Agriculture, Office of Experiment Stations Bulletin 72: pages 1-23 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1899 (Box 19, Folder 90)
    - Some Facts and Fancies, Old or New, In Horticulture 33red Annual Report, Secretary of the Board of Agriculture for 1899 pages 45-55; discussion: pages 55-75, 1900 (Box 19, Folder 91)
      Address delivered before Farmer's Convention at Meriden, Connecticut, December 13, 1899; discussion not pertinent to Bailey omitted; two copies - one, a reprint.
    - The Problem of Impoverished Lands. Being Suggestions for Investigation and Experiment. Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station - Horticultural Division Bulletin 174 Author: L. H. Bailey, November 1899 (Box 19, Folder 92)
    - What is Nature-Study? The Sanitary Home pages 61-63 Author: L. H. Bailey, May 1899 (Box 19, Folder 93)
      same article as the on folder 86
    - The Evolution of a Strawberry The Independent pages 256-260 Author: L. H. Bailey, January 1899 (Box 19, Folder 94)
    - An Evolutionist's View of Nature and Religion The Indecent pages 335-339 Author: L. H. Bailey, January 1899 (Box 19, Folder 94)
    - Waiting For the Birds Junior-Naturalist Monthly, Issued by the College of Agriculture and Experiment Station of Cornell University Volume 1, No. 5: pages 1-4 Author: L. H. Bailey, February 1900 (Box 19, Folder 95)
    - A Children's Garden Junior-Naturalist Monthly, Issued by the College of Agriculture and Experiment Station of Cornell University Volume 1, No.8: pages 1-4 Author: L. H. Bailey, May 1900 (Box 19, Folder 96)
    - Autumn Leaves Junior-Naturalist Monthly, Issued by the College of Agriculture and Experiment Station of Cornell University Volume 2, No.9: page 1 Author: L. H. Bailey, October 1900 (Box 19, Folder 97)
    - Robin! Junior-Naturalist Monthly, Issued by the College of Agriculture and Experiment Station of Cornell University Volume 3, No. 2: page 1 Author: L. H. Bailey, March 1901 (Box 19, Folder 98)
    - The Abandoned Farms Country Life in America Volume 1, No. 1: pages 3-8 Author: L. H. Bailey, November 1901 (Box 19, Folder 99)
    - Ellerslie, An American Country Seat Country Life in America Volume 1, No. 1: pages 9-13 Author: L. H. Bailey, November 1901 (Box 19, Folder 100)
    - What This Magazine Stands For Country Life in America Volume 1, No. 1: pages 24-25 Author: L. H. Bailey, November 1901 (Box 19, Folder 101)
    - How to Make a Garden - The First Lesson Country Life in America Volume 1, No. 1: pages 31-32 Author: L. H. Bailey, November 1901 (Box 19, Folder 102)
    - An Outlook on Winter Country Life in America Volume 1, No. 2: pages 37-40 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1901 (Box 19, Folder 103)
    - On the Making of Herbaceous Borders: Some Lessons From the Pan-American Exposition Country Life in America Volume 1, No. 2: pages 56-57 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1901 (Box 19, Folder 104)
    - Specimen Plants: Some of the Ideals in Plant Growing - What the Gardener Means By a "Well-Grown" Plant Country Life in America Volume 1, No. 2: page 66 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1901 (Box 19, Folder 105)
    - The Lesson of the Abandoned Farms Country Life in America Volume 1, No. 2: pages 58-59 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1901 (Box 19, Folder 106)
    - Lessons in Horticulture, Fruit Growing, Floriculture, etc. The Home Correspondence School 29 pages Author: L. H. Bailey, 1902 (Box 19, Folder 107)
    - The Problem of the West Country Life in America Volume 1, No. 3: pages 92-93 Author: L. H. Bailey, January 1902 (Box 19, Folder 108)
    - California Country Life in America Volume 1, No. 3: pages 71-75 Author: L. H. Bailey, January 1902 (Box 19, Folder 109)
    - The Nature-Study Idea Country Life in America Volume 1, No. 4: pages 128-129 Author: L. H. Bailey, February 1902 (Box 19, Folder 110)
    - Notes on Various Topics; On Native Sparrows; Food of Nesting Birds; Where the Coconut Came From. Country Life in America Volume 1, No. 5: pages lxxiv-lxxv Author: L. H. Bailey, March 1902 (Box 19, Folder 111)
    - The Greenhouse in the Snow Country Life in America Volume 1, No. 5: pages 168-169 Author: L. H. Bailey, March 1902 (Box 19, Folder 112)
    - The Return to the Soil Country Life in America Volume 1, No. 5: pages 170-171 Author: L. H. Bailey, March 1902 (Box 19, Folder 113)
    - The Making of a Country Home Country Life in America Volume 1, No. 6: pages 200-202 Author: L. H. Bailey, April 1902 (Box 19, Folder 114)
    - The New Hunting Country Life in America Volume 1, No. 6: pages 214-215 Author: L. H. Bailey, April 1902 (Box 19, Folder 115)
    - How to Make a Garden - Digging in the Dirt Country Life in America Volume 1, No. 6: pages 217-218 Author: L. H. Bailey, April 1902 (Box 19, Folder 116)
    - How Frank and Henry Raised Chickens Junior-Naturalist Monthly, Issued by the College of Agriculture and Experiment Station of Cornell University Volume 5, No. 2: page 8 Author: L. H. Bailey, November 1902 (Box 19, Folder 117)
    - Current Tendencies in Agricultural Education New York State Report of the Bureau of Farmer's Institutes pages 161-166 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1903 (Box 19, Folder 118)
    - The Forward Movement in Plant-Breeding Proceedings of the 42nd American Philosophical Society pages 54-68 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1903 (Box 19, Folder 119)
    - Baldwin and Ben Davis Proceedings of 48th Annual Meeting, The Western New York Horticultural Society pages 41-50 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1903 (Box 19, Folder 120)
      Held at Rochester, NY, January 28-29, 1903
    - An Apple Twig and An Apple Junior-Naturalist Monthly, Issued by the College of Agriculture and Experiment Station of Cornell University Volume 5, No. 4: pages 1-5 Author: L. H. Bailey, January 1903 (Box 19, Folder 121)
    - Some Recent Ideas of the Evolution of Plants Science N.S. Volume 17, No. 429: pages 441-454 Author: L. H. Bailey, March 1903 (Box 19, Folder 122)
    - How To Make a Living Out-Of-Doors - I. Dairy Farming Country Life in America Volume 5, No.1: pages 11-15 Author: L. H. Bailey, November.1903 (Box 19, Folder 123)
    - How To Make a Living From the Land - III. A Rose Garden Under Glass Country Life in America Volume 5, No. 4: pages 289-292,333-334 Author: L. H. Bailey, February 1904 (Box 19, Folder 123)
    - How To Make a Living From the Land - IV. The Story of a Bermudan Garden-Farmer Country Life in America Volume 5, No. 4: pages 505-507 Author: L. H. Bailey, April 1904 (Box 19, Folder 123)
      Photos by L.H. Bailey except for headpiece and pg. 506
    - How To Make a Living From the Land - V. The Making of Clean Milk Country Life in America Volume 6, No. 2: pages 170-172 Author: L. H. Bailey, June 1904 (Box 19, Folder 123)
    - How To Make a Living From the Land - VI. Sheep Ranching in the Northwest Country Life in America Volume 6, No. 3: pages 256-258,286-287 Author: L. H. Bailey, July 1904 (Box 19, Folder 123)
    - How To Make a Living From the Land - VII. The Making of Cheese in the Mohawk Valley Country Life in America Volume 6, No. 4: pages 353-354 Author: L. H. Bailey, August 1904 (Box 19, Folder 123)
    - How To Make a Living From the Land - VIII. Going Back to the Old Farm Country Life in America Volume 6, No. 5: pages 435-437 Author: L. H. Bailey, September 1904 (Box 19, Folder 123)
    - The Outlook For Agricultural Teaching Cornell Countryman Volume 1, No. 1: pages 3-5 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1903 (Box 19, Folder 124)
    - The New Education Country Life in America Volume 5, No. 1: pages 34-35 Author: L. H. Bailey, November 1903 (Box 19, Folder 125)